
// GAME QUESTIONS
// EASY
let easyGameQuestions = [
   {
      question: "What is the capital of Palestine ?",
      option: [`
      A) Rafaq 
      B) Abu Dabi 
      C) Jerusalem
      `],
      answer: "JERUSALEM"
   },
   {
      question: 'How old was prophet Muhammad pbuh when he died? ',
      option: [`
      A) 30 
      B) 63 
      C) 28
      `],
      answer: '63',
   },
   {
      question: 'Who was `Khaleed ibn Waleed ?`',
      option: [`
      A) sahabah 
      B) poem 
      C) president `],
      answer: 'SAHABAH'
   },
   {
      question: 'Where did Islamic religion start?`',
      option: [`
      A) Madina
      B) Mecca 
      C) Jerusalem `],
      answer: 'MECCA'
   },
   {
      question: 'What is the holy book in Islam',
      option: [`
      A) Quran 
      B) Torah 
      C) Bible` ],
      answer: 'QURAN'
   },
   {
      question: 'How many surahs does Quran contain?',
      option: [`
      A) 110 
      B) 128 
      C) 114 
      `],
      answer: '114'
   },
   {
      question: 'What is the holy book in Jews?',
      option: [`
      A) Quran 
      B) Torah 
      C Bible
      `],
      answer: 'TORAH'
   },
   {
      question: 'Who was the mother of Isa (AS)?',
      option: [`
      A) Maryam 
      B) Khadija 
      C) Asiya
      `],
      answer: 'MARYAM'
   },
   {
      question: 'Who was the wife of Pharaoh',
      option: [`
      A) Maryam 
      B) Khadija 
      C) Asiya 
      `],
      answer: 'ASIYA'
   },
   {
      question: 'Who was the first man on earth?',
      option: [`
      A) Adam (AS) 
      B) Musa (AS) 
      C Ibrahim (AS)
      `],
      answer: 'ADAM (AS)'
   },
];
// MEDIUM
let mediumGameQuestions = [
   {
      question: "Which angel is the head one in Jahannam?",
      option: [`
      A) Jibril 
      B) Maalik 
      C) Azrail
      `],
      answer: "MAALIK"
   },
   {
      question: 'How old will people be in Jannah ? ',
      option: [`
      A) 30 
      B) 25 
      C) 33
      `],
      answer: '33',
   },
   {
      question: `Which countries were conquered during Abu Bakr Siddiq (ra)'s time `,
      option: [`
      A) Iraq and Syria
      B) Iraq and Rum 
      C) Rum and Iran 
      `],
      answer: 'IRAQ AND SYRIA'
   },
   {
      question: `Which cave was shelter for prophet Muhammad (saw) and Abu Bakr (ra) when emigrating to Madina?`,
      option: [`
      A) Savr
      B) Hira 
      C) Nur `],
      answer: 'SAVR'
   },
   {
      question: `What was the name of the camel which our prophet Muhammad (saw) rode to Madina when emigrating ?`,
      option: [`
      A) Azboa 
      B) Jado 
      C) Qaswa` ],
      answer: 'QASWA'
   },
   {
      question: 'How many days did prophet Muhammad pbuh and Abu Bakr (ra) stay in the cave when emigrating ?',
      option: [`
      A) 1 
      B) 2 
      C) 3 
      `],
      answer: '3'
   },
   {
      question: `Which mosque was built first after prophecy`,
      option: [`
      A) Qubo 
      B) Nabiy 
      C) Aqso
      `],
      answer: 'QUBO'
   },
   {
      question: `Who was the man that was mentioned in the Quran as a blind man?`,
      option: [`
      A) Abdulloh ibn Ummi Maktum 
      B) Talha ibn Ubaydulloh 
      C) Zubayr ibn Avvom
      `],
      answer: 'ABDULLOH IBN UMMI MAKTUM'
   },
   {
      question: 'Who was the first child who converted to Islam ?',
      option: [`
      A) Ali (ra) 
      B) Zubayr (ra) 
      C) Urwa (ra) 
      `],
      answer: 'ALI (RA)'
   },
   {
      question: `Who was Haroon (as) of this Ummah ?`,
      option: [`
      A) Urwa (ra)
      B) Zubayr (ra) 
      C) Ali (ra)
      `],
      answer: 'ALI (RA)'
   },
];
// HARD 
let hardGameQuestions = [
   {
      question: "1. Find Abu Lahaba's son's name!",
      option: [`
      A) Kannon 
      B) Utayba 
      C) Seen
      `],
      answer: "UTAYBA"
   },
   {
      question: '2. What was the name of the donkey of prophet Muhammad pbuh ?',
      option: [`
      A) Ya'foor 
      B) Ya'sar 
      C) Joondooq
      `],
      answer: `YA'FOOR`,
   },
   {
      question: `3. What is the meaning of Ya'foor ? `,
      option: [`
      A) Deer
      B) Tiger 
      C) Lion 
      `],
      answer: 'DEER'
   },
   {
      question: `4. Which Prophet (as) had control of the Jinn and was able to talk to animals?`,
      option: [`
      A) Sulaiman (as)
      B) Dawud (as) 
      C) Musa (as) `],
      answer: 'SULAIMAN (AS)'
   },
   {
      question: `5. What does Zam Zam mean ?`,
      option: [`
      A) Drink 
      B) Cure 
      C) Stop` ],
      answer: 'STOP'
   },
   {
      question: '6. What was the relationship between Prophet Musa (as) and Propet Haroon (as) ?',
      option: [`
      A) Cousins 
      B) Brothers 
      C) Friends 
      `],
      answer: 'BROTHERS'
   },
   {
      question: `7. Who was a first cousin of Prophet Muhammad pbuh ?`,
      option: [`
      A) Abbos (ra) 
      B) Umar (ra) 
      C) Waleed (ra)
      `],
      answer: 'ABBOS (RA)'
   },
   {
      question: `8. What issue was was Imam al-Bukhari born with ?`,
      option: [`
      A) Blind 
      B) Deaf
      C) Heartache
      `],
      answer: 'BLIND'
   },
   {
      question: '9. In Jannah, what is Tuba ?',
      option: [`
      A) fruit
      B) tree 
      C) door
      `],
      answer: 'TREE'
   },
   {
      question: `10. Which two surahs are for seeking protection in Allah from evil-eye and witchcraft ?`,
      option: [`
      A) Yaseen and Ikhlas.
      B) Falaq and Naas 
      C) Yusoof and Kakhf
      `],
      answer: 'FALAQ AND NAAS'
   },
];
// QUESTIONS ABOUT USER
let questionsAboutUser = [
   `
   ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
      COULD YOU TELL US YOUR
      NAME?
   ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
   `,
   `~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
      COULD YOU TELL US YOUR
      AGE?
    ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~  
   `
];

// ~~~~~~<><><>------<><><>~~~~~

// 1. ASK ABOUT USER FUNCTION
let aboutUserIndex = 0;
let aboutAnswers = [];
let userName;
function askAboutUser(){
   alert(`~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
         HELLO ! 
         WELCOME TO THE GAME!
         THIS GAME IS GONNA TEST 
         YOUR ISLAMIC KNOWLEDGE!
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~                                                         
                               -------------
                              | Press ENTER |
                               -------------
   ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
   `)
   alert(`~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~                       
         SERVING FOR YOU IS GREAT HONOUR     
         FOR US !!!                    
         ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~                                                            
                                 -------------
                                | Press ENTER |
                                 -------------`)
   while(aboutUserIndex < questionsAboutUser.length){

      let aboutAnswer = prompt(questionsAboutUser[aboutUserIndex])
      let upperAboutAnswer = aboutAnswer.toLocaleUpperCase()
      if(!upperAboutAnswer){
         continue;

      }else{
         aboutAnswers.push(upperAboutAnswer)

         userName = aboutAnswers[0]
         aboutUserIndex++
      }
   }
   
   playGame()
}

// 2. ASK USER TO PLAY OR NOT
function playGame(){
   let agree = prompt(`
   <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
   
   ${userName}, do you wanna test your knowledge ? [YES/NO] 

   <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
   
   `);
   let upperAgree = agree.toUpperCase()

   if(upperAgree === 'YES'){
      showManual()
   }else if(upperAgree === 'NO'){
      alert(`
      <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
      
      I hope you come later again!

      <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
      `)
   }else{
      alert(`
      <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>

      Invalid answer.

      <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
      `)
   }
}

// 3. CHOOSE LEVEL FUNCTION
function chooseLevel(){
   let receiveLevel = prompt(`PLEASE CHOOSE YOUR LEVEL:
         ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
               | EASY
               | MEDIUM
               | HARD
         ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

   `)

   let upperReceiveLevel = receiveLevel.toUpperCase();
   if(upperReceiveLevel == 'EASY'){
      askQuestion(easyGameQuestions);
   }else if(upperReceiveLevel == 'MEDIUM'){
      askQuestion(mediumGameQuestions);
   }else if(upperReceiveLevel == 'HARD'){
      askQuestion(hardGameQuestions);
   }else{
      alert('Invalid level!')
   }
}

// 4. MANUAL
function showManual(){
   alert(`
      !<><><><><><><><><{ MANUAL }<><><><><><><><>!

      1. Please, be careful for extra spaces it is gonna 
      cause a problem!

      2. Don't worry about capital, upper, and lower 
      cases, the program is gonna fix them!

      ~~~~~~~~~~~~~ Press {ENTER} to start ~~~~~~~~~~~
      !<><><><><><><><><><>----<><><><><><><><><><>!
      `)
      chooseLevel()
      
}
// ------ ------ ------ ------

// 5. GAME QUESTIONS FUNCTION

let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
let rightAnswers = []
let wrongAnswers = []

function askQuestion(level){
   while(currentQuestionIndex < level.length){

      let checkAnswer = prompt(`
      <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
      ${level[currentQuestionIndex].question}  
      ${level[currentQuestionIndex].option}
      <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
      `)
      let upperCheckAnswer = checkAnswer.toUpperCase();
      if(!upperCheckAnswer.toUpperCase()){
         continue;
      }else if(upperCheckAnswer !== level[currentQuestionIndex].answer){
         wrongAnswers++

      }else{
         rightAnswers++

      }
      currentQuestionIndex++
   }
   
   console.log(`
      ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ <><><><> ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~~
      ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ <><><><> ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~~

            Right answers: ${rightAnswers}
            ------ ----- ---- 
            Wrong answers: ${wrongAnswers}

      ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ <><><><> ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~~
      ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ <><><><> ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~~
   `);
   giveComment()
} 

// 6. GIVE COMMENT
function giveComment(){

      if(rightAnswers >= 10){
         alert(`
            <>~~~~<>~~~~~<Comment>~~~~~<>~~~~<>
            ~ Barakalloh, MashaAlloh! ${userName} May Alloh 
              give you more than that!
            ~ You found ${rightAnswers} out of ${easyGameQuestions.length}.
            ~ You are bunderkind !!!
            <>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>
         `);

      }else if(rightAnswers >= 8){
         alert(`
            <>~~~~<>~~~~~<Comment>~~~~~<>~~~~<>
            ~ Barakalloh, MashaAlloh! ${userName}, you are
              really close to bundergind!
            ~ You found ${rightAnswers} out of ${easyGameQuestions.length} questions.

            ~ You have got high knowledge!
            <>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>
         `);
      }else if(rightAnswers >= 6){
         alert(
            `
            <>~~~~<>~~~~~<Comment>~~~~~<>~~~~<>
            ~ Barakalloh, MashaAlloh! ${userName}, you 
              should work on you!
            ~ You found ${rightAnswers} out of ${easyGameQuestions.length} questions.

            ~ You have a medium Islamic knowledge !!!
             <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~~<>
            `
         );
      }else if(rightAnswers >= 2){
         alert(`
            <>~~~~<>~~~~~<Comment>~~~~~<>~~~~<>
            ~ ${userName}, may Allah have mercy on you! 
              It is really bad not knowing this basic 
              knowledge.
            ~ You found ${rightAnswers} out of ${easyGameQuestions.length} questions.
         
            ~ You did not well !!!
            <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
            `
         );
      }else {
         alert(`
            <>~~~~<>~~~~~<Comment>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
            ~ ${userName}, may Allah have mercy on you! 
              It is really bad not knowing this basic 
              knowledge.
            ~ You found 0 out of ${easyGameQuestions.length}.
              
            ~ It can not be worse than this!
            <>~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~~<>~~~~<>~~~~<>
            `);
      }
}



// LAST [HEAD] GAME OPERATOR
function gameOperator(){
   askAboutUser()
}

gameOperator()
